<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>

<?xml-stylesheet href="./_c74_ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<!--This is an automatically generated file. DO NOT EDIT THIS FILE DIRECTLY. Rather, use the _ref.xml files found in the 'edits' folder.-->
<c74object name="ta.urn" module="max" category="Math">
	<digest>
		Generate random numbers without duplicates
	</digest>
	<description>
		Similar to <o>urn</o> but it makes sure no output numbers are repeated. 
	</description>
	<!--METADATA-->
	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">
			Tiago Ângelo
		</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">
			TA-Library
		</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">
			Math
		</metadata>
	</metadatalist>
	<!--INLETS-->
	<inletlist>
		<inlet id="0" type="INLET_TYPE">
			<digest>
				bang Generates Random Number
			</digest>
			<description>
				TEXT_HERE
			</description>
		</inlet>
		<inlet id="1" type="INLET_TYPE">
			<digest>
				Set Range of Random Numbers
			</digest>
			<description>
				TEXT_HERE
			</description>
		</inlet>
	</inletlist>
	<!--OUTLETS-->
	<outletlist>
		<outlet id="0" type="OUTLET_TYPE">
			<digest>
				Random Number Output
			</digest>
			<description>
				TEXT_HERE
			</description>
		</outlet>
	</outletlist>
	<!--ARGUMENTS-->
	<objarglist>
		<objarg name="limit" optional="1" type="int">
			<digest>
				Random number limit
			</digest>
			<description>
				The number of possible values for the random number generator. If no argument is typed in, there will be only <m>1</m> possible number.
			</description>
		</objarg>
		<objarg name="seed" optional="1" type="int">
			<digest>
				Random generator seed
			</digest>
			<description>
				A second argument is used to set a &quot;seed&quot; value for the random generator. If no argument is specified, the time value will be used to initialize the seed.
			</description>
		</objarg>
	</objarglist>
	<!--MESSAGES-->
	<methodlist>
		<method name="bang">
			<arglist />
			<digest>
				Output random number
			</digest>
			<description>
				In left inlet: Sends out a previously unchosen random number from 0 to one less than the specified maximum limit.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="int">
			<arglist>
				<arg name="limit" optional="0" type="int" />
			</arglist>
			<digest>
				Set random number limit
			</digest>
			<description>
				In right inlet: Clears the list of already chosen numbers, and specifies the number of possible values for the random number generator. The random numbers will range from 0 to one less than this maximum limit.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="clear">
			<arglist />
			<digest>
				Clear the list of output numbers
			</digest>
			<description>
				In left inlet: Clears the list of already chosen numbers.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="in1">
			<arglist>
				<arg name="limit" optional="0" type="int" />
			</arglist>
			<digest>
				Set random number limit
			</digest>
			<description>
				Clears the list of already chosen numbers, and specifies the number of possible values for the random number generator. The random numbers will range from 0 to one less than this maximum limit.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="seed">
			<arglist>
				<arg name="seed" optional="0" type="int" />
			</arglist>
			<digest>
				Seed the random generator
			</digest>
			<description>
				In left inlet: The word <m>seed</m>, followed by a number, provides a &quot;seed&quot; value for the random generator, which causes a specific (reproducible) sequence of pseudo-random numbers to occur. The number <m>0</m> uses the time elapsed since system startup (an unpredictable value) as the seed, ensuring an unpredictable sequence of numbers. This unpredictable seed is used by default when the <o>urn</o> object is created. However, once all numbers have been chosen, the sequence will repeat. Therefore, in order to achieve a non-repeating sequence of numbers, you will need to send the <o>urn</o> object the <m>seed 0</m> message each time you send it the <m>clear</m> message.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>
	<!--ATTRIBUTES-->
	<!--EXAMPLE-->
	<examplelist>
		<example img="" caption="Urn comparison" />
	</examplelist>
	<!--SEEALSO-->
	<seealsolist>
		<seealso name="decide" />
		<seealso name="deferlow" />
		<seealso name="drunk" />
		<seealso name="random" />
	</seealsolist>
	<misc name="Output">
		<entry name="int">
			<description>
				Out left outlet: If there are numbers within the current range that have not been sent out since the last <m>clear</m> message was received, <o>urn</o> generates a random number between 0 and one less than the maximum.
			</description>
		</entry>
		<entry name="bang">
			<description>
				Out right outlet: When all numbers in the current range have been generated, <o>urn</o> sends a <m>bang</m> out the right outlet instead of a number out the left outlet.
			</description>
		</entry>
	</misc>
</c74object>
